Mark Peterson

1431 Pat Tillman Street, De Pere,WI 54115

Phone:920.264.8243 | Email: mwpx777@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mwpdesigns/ | GitHub: https://github.com/mwpx777

Portfolio: https://mwpx777.github.io/Mark-Peterson-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Front-end web developer with five years of graphic design experience. Collaborated with freelance customers in taking a visionary concept to a finished, successful product. Self motivated to grow technical skills. Recent graduate of the University of Wisconsin Web Development Bootcamp.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery

Applications: Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, G suite,

PROJECTS

Movie Database Search | https://github.com/mwpx777/Movie-Database-Search | https://mwpx777.github.io/Movie-Database-Search/

- The application will access the IMDB and Utelly APIs to search for movie information and where the movie is available for streaming.
- Team leader for the first group project. Designed the basic app layout and implemented the IMDB API.
- Use of HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, and Adobe Illustrator

Weather Search Dashboard | https://github.com/mwpx777/Weather-Dashboard | https://mwpx777.github.io/Weather-Dashboard |

- The application will search OpenWeather API for current weather and 5 day forecast for a selected city.
- Utilized third party API to display content on this website
- Use of HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, and Moment.js

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Graphic Artist and Digital Sculptor MWP Designs

2018-Present De Pere, WI

Create conceptual artwork and digital designs utilizing Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator. Create 3D digital sculptures for custom minting and silver sand casting. Work closely with artists and sculptors to collaborate on innovative designs and artwork. Create digital artwork used for

T-shirts, product packaging and social media promotion.

Key Accomplishments:

- Strengthened social media presence which increased the customer base by 70% in the last year
- Cultivated business relationships which led to resulted in an increase of business revenue by 100% from 2019 to 2020
- Donated digital sculptures for fundraising efforts for COVID PPE and Toys for Tots

Graphic Artist and Digital Sculptor Medalcraft Mint Inc.

2005-2020 Green Bay, WI

Create 3D digital sculptures utilizing ArtCAM from customer supplied artwork. Collaborate with customers to develop their ideas into a manufacturable product. Create concept artwork utilizing Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator. Program and toolpath 2D and 3D dies for CNC machining. Operate 3D scanner for digitizing customer supplied plaster sculptures.

Key Accomplishments:

- Designed and digitally sculpted the official 2013 Presidential Inaugural Medallion reverse
- Increased department production by 50% by mastering a new software package and training staff

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Tool and Die Apprenticeship Certificate : Northeast Wisconsin Technical College, Green Bay, WI

Completed State of Wisconsin regulated Journeyman Tool and Die apprenticeship. Completed 10,400 hours of on job training along with 600 hours of classroom instruction.